Contact

drewdrewpeters45@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/drew-peters-23b048223 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

React.js Node.js MERN Stack

Drew Peters

Senior JavaScript Developer - React, Node, Angular, Vue Glenmont

Summary

I'm a highly-skilled, senior web developer with 9+ yrs of experience in responsive web development using React, Angular, Vue, Node, Express, Redux, Next, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, and the cloud platform at New York's leading IT companies. My work experience runs a wide range of software development, from software architecture, database design to website/web app/mobile app development.

I have worked with the Agile development methodology to build testdriven code both as a developer and as a scrum master.

Also, I work well with other team members (mentoring and leadership) and always find the opportunity to brainstorm.

I love creative, innovative companies/clients who focus on improving their products, as well as the growth of their employees.

My other interests include sports, music, and gaming.

I am a proven troubleshooter who works well with other team members and I have worked with Agile Development, building testdriven code both as a developer and as a scrum master.

In my personal life, I enjoy spending time with friends and family, as well as almost any outdoor activity.

Experience

Blue Label Labs Full-stack Web Developer 2019 - June 2021 (2 years) New York, NY, United States

• Exploited Node.js's ability to handle a large number of concurrent requests by using Express to develop an API for serving proprietary data to clients from a SQL database, and mentored junior developers by conducting group and one-on-one code reviews, and instructing on best practices and fostering an empathetic group environment.

Techs used: React, Node, Express, Angular, Vue, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, AWS.

Mobikasa Senior Web Developer 2016 - 2018 (2 years)

New York, NY, United States

 Used React to build a scalable application by creating reusable components to ensure modularity, and created and customized frontend themes and templates for event websites to maintain reusability and modularity and supported several long-term projects, feature development, bug fixes, and general website maintenance.

Techs used: React, Node, Express, Angular, Vue, JavaScript, TypeScript, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

Lform Design
Javascript Developer
2013 - 2015 (2 years)
New York, NY, United States

 Increased user traffic and engagement by 30% by optimizing SEO and website/application speed using CDNs, dynamic images, and minimizing external HTTP requests, incorporating a UX-driven design strategy, and engineered test-driven development using Jest and Enzyme to ensure application functionality persists through feature updates and releases.
 Techs used: Vue, React, Tailwind, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, TypeScript, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

RMG

Software Engineer
June 2011 - May 2012 (1 year)
New York, NY, United States

• Developed a client-facing portal to enable users to access collections of data/biographies with user authentication and worked cross-functionally utilizing a SQL database and a web scripting language-based CMS to manage complex interrelated data to enable efficient querying of user biographies and content. Techs used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, MySQL, and Apache.

Education

Columbia University in the City of New York

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science · (2006 - 2010)